Elisha Kent Kane Papers 1810-1973 1843-1857 Mss.B.K132
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1810-1953 (bulk: 1843-1857); 5.5 linear feet
  - 1849, n.d., 4 items; Dunlap, Mr. (Box 2)
  - 1852 December 22, 1 item; Duval, W. L. (Box 2)
  - 1852 November 8, 1 item; Eaton, F. B. (Box 2)
  - 1852 March 31, 1 item; Edwards, D. S. (Box 2)
  - 1926 April 21, 1 item; Elder, Margaret M. (Box 2)
  - 1849 September 19, 1 item; Eldridge, Rebecca G. (Box 2)
  - 1853 February 15, 1 item; Elliot, C. B. (Box 2)
  - 1848 May 15, 1 item; Elliot, S. A. (Box 2)
  - 1855 May 28, 1 item; England, J. W. (Box 2)
  - 1852-1856, 2 items; Erwin, E. C. (Box 2)
  - Estate Inventory, n.d.; 3 items; Kane, J. D. L. (Box 2)
  - 1853 February 26, 1 item; Etheridge, John (Box 2)
  - 1846 May 17, 1 item; Everest, G. W. (Box 2)
  - n.d., 1 item; Everett, Col. (Box 2)
  - 1852, 2 items; Everett, Edward (Box 2)
  - 1853 February 5, 1 item; Farmers' and Mechanics' Bank in the City of Philadelphia. (Box 2)
  - 1852 January 28, 1 item; Fausard, Joshua (Box 2)
  - 1852, 2 items; Fellerer, E. (Box 2)
  - 1852 November 19, 1 item; Fellows, E. R. (Box 2)
  - 1852 November 16, 1 item; Fields, J. (Box 2)
  - n.d., 1 item; Fisher, Joshua Francis, 1807-1873 (Box 2)
  - 1852-1856, 5 items; Force, Peter, 1790-1868 (Box 2)
  - 1852, 4 items; Foreman, E. (Box 2)
  - n.d., 1 item; Foulke, Jean Kane (Box 2)
  - 1862 October 26, 1 item; Fox, Catherine (Box 2)
  - n.d., 1 item; Fox, J. L. (Box 2)
  - To Mrs. Ellet, n.d.; 2 items; Fox, Margaret (Box 2)
  - To Cornelius Grinnell, 1853-1855; 3 folders; Fox, Margaret (Box 2)
    - Folder 1, 1853-1854; 16 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 2, 1855-n.d.; 15 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 3, n.d.; 10 items (Box 2)
  - To Elisha Kent Kane, 1856, n.d.; 11 items; Fox, Margaret (Box 2)
  - To R. P. Kane, 1857-1860; 2 folders; Fox, Margaret (Box 2)
    - Folder 1, 1857-1858; 21 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 2, 1859-1860, n.d.; 15 items (Box 2)
  - To Mr. Philips, n.d.; 1 item; Fox, Margaret (Box 2)
  - To William Quinn, 1860; 3 items; Fox, Margaret (Box 2)
  - 1856 June 24, n.d., 2 items; Fox, Margaret (mother) (Box 2)
  - n.d., 1 item; Fox-Kane Correspondence (Box 2)
  - 1853; 1858-1860; 1862, 3 folders; Fox-Kane Correspondence (bundled by R. P. Kane) (Box 2)
    - Folder 1, 1853; 1858; 17 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 2, 1859-1860; 15 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 3, 1862; n.d.; 24 items (Box 2)
  - In re publication, n.d.; 1 item; Fox-Kane Correspondence (Box 2)
  - In re schooling, 1853; 8 items; Fox-Kane Correspondence (Box 2)
  - 1849-1857, 2 folders; Franklin, Jane Griffin, Lady, 1792-1875 (Box 3)
    - Folder 1, 1849-1852; 13 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 2, 1853-1857; 12 items (Box 3)
  - 1850, Freeland, Benjamin (Box 3)
    See Vreeland, Benjamin
  - 1847 November 23, 1 item; French, Benjamin (Box 3)
  - 1849, 3 items; Fronti, Gabriel (Box 3)
  - 1852 December 3, 1 item; Frost, C. C. (Box 3)
  - 1848, 2 items; Gaona, Macuin (Box 3)
  - 1848 May 27, 1 item; Garcia, J. M. (Box 3)
  - 1819-1828, 7 items; George, Joseph (Box 3)
  - 1849, 2 items; Ghiselin, J. D., Jr. (Box 3)
  - 1852 October 20, 1 item; Giddings, C. S. (Box 3)
  - 1852-1853, 2 items; Gleason, J. T. (Box 3)
  - n.d., 1 item; Goddard, Charles (Box 3)
  - 1853 May 12, 1 item; Goodfellow, Henry. (Box 3)
  - n.d., 1 item; Governor of Luxor (Box 3)
  - 1852 June 16, 1 item; Graham, W. A. (Box 3)
  - 1845 April 7, 1 item; Gray, N. B. (Box 3)
  - 1858, 3 items; Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872 (Box 3)
  - n.d., 1 item; Green, Dr. (Box 3)
  - 1847-1848, 3 items; Greene, James M. (Box 3)
  - 1853 January 13, 1 item; Gregg, O. O. (Box 3)
  - 1851-1856, 3 items; Greig, John (Box 3)
  - 1851-1857, 3 folders; Grinnell, Cornelius (Box 3)
    - Folder 1, 1851-1852; 17 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 2, 1853-1857; 9 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 3, n.d.; 15 items (Box 3)
  - 1851-1857, 3 folders; Grinnell, Henry (Box 3)
    - Folder 1, 1851-1852; 18 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 2, 1853; 14 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 3, 1854-1857; 15 items (Box 3)
  - 1854 April 28, 1 item; Grinnell, R. M. (Box 3)
  - 1852, 2 items; Gunnell, Francis B. (Box 3)
  - 1847 November 9, 1 item; Guthrie, J. B. (Box 3)
  - 1842 May 24, 1 item; Gutzlaff, Charles (Box 3)
  - 1855 February 7, 1 item; Gwin, W. M. (Box 3)
  - 1852-185-, 2 items; Hacker, W. P. (Box 3)
  - n.d., 1 item; Haghe, C. (Box 3)
  - 1846 January 20, 1 item; Haines, R. (Box 3)
  - 1852 October 11, 1 item; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783 (Box 3)
  - 1853 January 11, 1 item; Harper and Brothers (Box 3)
  - 1852-1853, 2 items; Harris, Samuel G. (Box 3)
  - 1847-1853, 2 folders; Harris, Thomas (Box 3)
    - Folder 1, 1847-1851; 15 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 2, 1852-1853, n.d.; 16 items (Box 3)
  - 1842-1852, 4 items; Harris, William (Box 3)
  - n.d., 1 item; Harrison, T. (Box 3)
  - 1853 April 16, 1 item; Hawkins, Rush C. (Box 3)
  - 1853, 2 items; Hawks, Francis L. (Box 3)
  - 1852-n.d., 3 items; Hays, Isaac Israel (Box 3)
  - 1848-n.d., 2 items; Hays, Otis (Box 3)
  - 1856 November 19, 1 item; Headley, G. T. (Box 3)
  - 1847, 2 items; Heiskell, H. L. (Box 3)
  - 1851, 4 items; Henry, Joseph (Box 3)
  - 1852-1853, 7 items; Hilgard, J. E. (Box 3)
  - 1852 January 28, 1 item; Hollins, R. S. (Box 3)
  - List of materials, 1852; 1 item; Horner, G. M. B. (Box 3)
  - 1855 October 9, 1 item; Hudson, Frederick (Box 3)
  - 1852 January 6, 1 item; Hughs, C. (Box 3)
  - 1853 March 8, 1 item; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859 (Box 3)
  - 1843 March 21, 1 item; Humphreys, Bevan (Box 3)
  - 1845 April 26, 1 item; Hunter, W. (Box 3)
  - n.d., 1 item; Hutchinson, Thomas (Box 3)
  - 1855-n.d., 3 items; Inglefield, E. A. (Box 3)
  - 1846, 2 items; Ingraham, Edward D. (Box 3)
  - n.d., 1 item; Ingraham, Miss (Box 3)
  - 1845, 1 item; Irving, Washington (Box 3)
  - 1853 January 24, 1 item; John Godsby and Son (Box 4)
  - 1852 February, 2 items; Johnson, G. N. (Box 4)
  - 1848, 4 items; Johnson, Thomas H. (Box 4)
  - 1852 January 21, 1 item; Jones, Alexander (Box 4)
  - 1841 January 21, 1 item; Joyner, L. S. (Box 4)
  - 1852 February 11, 1 item; Judkins, D. (Box 4)
  - n.d., 2 items; Justice, George (Box 4)
  - n.d., 1 item; Kane, C. V. L. (Box 4)
  - 1825-[1847?], 2 items; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 4)
  - Access to the North Pole, n.d.; 17 p., 2 copies; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 4)
  - Access to the North Pole, n.d.; 17 p.; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Oversize 1)
  - Africa: miscellaneous, ca.1846; 2 folders; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 4)
    - Folder 1, ca.1846; 9 p. (Box 4)
    - Folder 2, ca.1846; 26p. (Box 4)
      Includes census information on Africans recaptured and sent to Liberia, information on productions of Liberia, Meterological chart for Monrovia, November 1846, etc.
  - Agreement with Thomas Leiper Kane to resign commission, 1842 September 24; 2p.; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 4)
  - Arctic Expedition: Bills and Receipts, 1846-1855; 22 items; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 4)
  - Arctic Expedition: Diary, 1850-1851; 27p.; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 4)
  - Arctic Expedition: Library, n.d.; 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 4)
  - Arctic Expedition: Meteorlogical Observations, 1850-1851; 30p.; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 4)
  - Arctic Expedition: Meteorlogical Observations, 1853-1854; 2 p.; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 4)
  - Arctic Expedition: Meteorological charts, n.d.; 3 p.; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Oversize 1)
  - Arctic Expedition: miscellaneous, 1850-1853, n.d.; 22 folders; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 4)
    - Folder 1, 1850-1851 (Box 4)
    - Folder 2, 1850-1851 (Box 4)
    - Folder 3, 1852-1853 (Box 4)
    - Folders 4-22, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Arctic expedition proposal, 1852 November 23; AMs (3 p.); Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Arctic Expedition: Return of Deserters, 1856 December; 24 p.; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Arctic Expedition: Sick list, 1850-1851; 2 notebooks; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Arctic Expedition: Supplies, n.d.; 6 items; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Arctic Expedition: Whalefish Islands, etc., 14 p.; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Arctic expedition proposal, 1852 November 23; AMs (3 p.); Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Arctic Regions (notes), n.d.; AMs (12 p.); Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Arcticles that were in use of Elisha Kent Kane, n.d.; 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Bank check, 1844; 2 items; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Book of estimates, Macao, 1845; 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Canceled checks, 1852; 21 items; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Catalogue of the Library of the U.S.S. United States, 1846 May 9; 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Childhood notebook, n.d.; 1 notebook; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - China miscellaneous, 1844-1845; 3 folders; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
    - Folder 1, 1844; 4 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 2, 1844-1845 (Box 5)
    - Folder 3, 1844-1845 (Box 5)
  - China and India (notes), 1 notebook; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - China correspondence, 1844-1845; 8 items; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Claim for service as Cushing Mission physician, 1844; 3 items; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Climate (notes), n.d.; AMs (4 p.); Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Controversy on "Grinnell Land", 1 notebook; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Court martial material, n.d.; 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Curry recipes, n.d.; 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Description of his watch, n.d.; 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Egypt, etc. notebook, n.d.; 1 notebook, 5 p.; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Engineering notes, Charles Bonnycastle lectures, Univ. of Virginia, [ca. 18380]; 1 notebook; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Eskimo song, n.d.; 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Examinations taken at the African Hospital, 1841; 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Experiments on Lt. Morris' power to distinguish color, n.d.; 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 5)
  - Franklin, John. Plan for a rescue mission, n.d.; AMs (18 p.); Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 6)
  - Greenland notebook, AMs, 36 p.; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 6)
  - Hawaii, 1843; 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 6)
  - Last days and death, 1857; 14 items; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 6)
  - Lectures, n.d.; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 6)
    - Lecture I: Arctic Exploration, n.d.; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Lecture II: The probable fate of Sir John Franklin..., n.d.; 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Lecture III: Arctic travel, n.d.; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Letters of condolence on Kane's death, 1855-1861; 12 items; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 6)
  - List of medicines for J. Dent, 1845 January 20; 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 6)
  - Lock of hair, 1822; 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 6)
  - To J. K. Kane (Gift from Eliza Cope Harrison and Robert Normandy Cope), 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 6)
  - To Maggie Fox, n.d.; 2 items; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 6)
  - Manila - rough notes, n.d.; 7 items; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 6)
  - Maps, charts, graphs, n.d.; 15 items; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 6)
    - Bolivia and Paraguay, 1 map, 21.6 x 22.2 cm; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857
      Colored.
      Other Finding Aids note
      Realms of Gold, 23 (5).
    - Bon Secour Bay, n.d.; 1 map, 25.4 x 19.7 cm; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857
      Realms of Gold, 23 (6).
    - British Isles, n.d.; 1 map, 19.7 x 22.9 cm; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857
      Realms of Gold, 23 (7).
    - Map of Baffin's Bay, n.d.; 1 map, 24.1 x 19.7 cm; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857
      Realms of Gold, 23 (8).
    - Melville Bay and Sylva Mountain Maps, 1853-1855; 172.3: 1853-1855: G895exp: Large; 4.0 Item(s) (Map-case Large)
      - Melville Bay and surrounding area, 1853-1855; 1 map, 60.4 x 73 cm; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Map-case Large)
        Realms of Gold, 23 (1).
      - Base of Sylva Mountain, observatory and brig, 1853-1855; 1 map, 44.8 x 63.4 cm; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Map-case Large)
        Draft.
        Realms of Gold, 23 (2).
      - Sylva Mountain, position of brigg and observatory, 1853-1855; 1 map, 18.3 x 20.8 cm; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Map-case Large)
        Realms of Gold, 23 (3).
      - Unidentified, 1853-1855; 1 map, 44.8 x 63.4 cm; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Map-case Large)
        Realms of Gold, 23 (4).
    - Mobile Bay, Alabama, n.d.; 1 map, 25.4 x 19.7 cm; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857
      Realms of Gold, 23 (10).
    - Mobile Bay, Alabama, n.d.; 1 map, 25.4 x 19.7 cm; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857
      Realms of Gold, 23 (11).
    - Northernmost penetration of the first Kane expedition, n.d.; 1 map, 32.4 x 50.5 cm; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857
      Realms of Gold, 23 (9).
    - Unidentified maps, n.d.; 6.0 Item(s); Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857
      Realms of Gold, 23 (12).
  - Medical notes, n.d.; 2 folders; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 6)
  - Memoranda. Baffin's Bay, Lancaster Sound, 1851-1852; 1 notebook; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 6)
  - Memorandum of cash advanced on account of copyright, 1855; 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 6)
  - Meteorological Journal, North Africa, 1835; AMs (12 p.); Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 6)
  - Meteorological observations-Sierra Leone, Freetown, n.d.; 13 items; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 6)
  - Mexico, n.d.; 8 items; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 6)
  - Miscellany, n.d.; 5 folders; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Notebook, n.d.; 1 notebook; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Passport, 1843 August 13; 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Pay voucher, 1848-1852; AMs (4 p.); Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Pemican, n.d.; 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Philippines notebooks, [1844]; 7 notebooks; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
    Notebooks identified as #1, 3-8
  - Philippines notebook, [1844]?; 1 notebook; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Poetry, 1935-n.d.; 3 items; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Power of attorney to J. K. Kane, 1850 May 20; AMs (1 p.); Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Power of attorney to J. K. Kane, 1850 May 26; AMs (1 p.); Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Receipt for a Haggis, n.d.; AMs (1 p.); Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Report on discovery of "Grinnell Land", AMs (7 p.); Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Rio de Janeiro, n.d; AMs (4 p.); Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Rough Notes of the Ke-Ying Visit, Macao, 1844; AMs, 16 p.; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Sketch of ship floor plan, n.d.; 1 drawing; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Sketches, n.d.; 2 folders; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Slave Voyage Notebook, n.d.; 1 notebook, 4 p.; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Spirit thermometers, n.d.; 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - "Testimonials" and "letters scr. for Dr. E. K. Kane", 1843 March; 1 item; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Travel notes, miscellaneous, n.d.; AMs (24 p.); Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Whampoa medical affairs, 1844; AMs (6 p.); Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Will, 1857; 2 items; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
  - Unidentified correspondent, 1843-1852, n.d.; 5 folders; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857 (Box 7)
    - Folder 1, 1843-1852; 7 items (Box 7)
    - Folders 2-5, n. d. (Box 7)
  - 1952, n.d., 4 items; Kane, Elizabeth (Box 7)
  - 1850-1853, 6 items; Kane, Family (Box 7)
  - 1921 December 20, 1 item; Kane, Francis Fisher, 1866-1955 (Box 7)
  - n.d., 1 item; Kane, Jack and Willie (Box 7)
  - n.d., 1 item; Kane, James (Box 7)
  - 1828-1856, n.d., 5 folders; Kane, Jane D. L. (Box 7)
    - Folder 1, 1828-1846; 15 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1847-1848; 13 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 3, 1849-1850; 16 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 4, 1851-1856; 11 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 5, n.d.; 23 items (Box 7)
  - 1841-1857, n.d., 6 folders; Kane, John K., (John Kintzing), 1795-1858 (Box 8)
    - Folder 1, 1841-1846; 13 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 2, 1847-1849; 17 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 3, 1850-1852; 10 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 4, 1853-1857; 11 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 5, n.d.; 36 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 6, n.d.; 26 items (Box 8)
  - 1846-1847, 5 items; Kane, John Kintzing, Jr. (Box 8)
  - 1847 November 8, 1 item; Kane, M., Jr. (Box 8)
  - 1844-1859, n.d., 3 folders; Kane, Robert Patterson, 1827-1906 (Box 8)
    - Folder 1, 1844-1859; 23 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 13 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 3, n.d.; 17 items (Box 8)
  - Letters to Margaret Fox, 1858-1859; 8 items; Kane, Robert Patterson, 1827-1906 (Box 8)
  - 1844-1860, 5 folders; Kane, Thomas Leiper, 1822-1883 (Box 8)
    - Folder 1, 1844-1846; 11 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 2, 1847-1850; 11 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 3, 1851-1860; 13 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 4, n.d.; 24 items (Box 8)
    - Correspondence with other Kane family members (Box 8)
  - 1844-1849, 11 items; Kane, William L. (Box 8)
  - n.d., 1 item; Kane Bros. and Co. (Box 8)
  - 1850-1853, 6 items; Kane Family (Box 8)
  - 1846-1852, 5 items; Kearney, John A. (Box 8)
  - 1854 September 27, 1 item; Kelly, P. E. (Box 8)
  - 1848, n.d., 2 items; Kemp, Mrs. V. (Box 8)
  - 1849 December 25, 1 item; Kennedy, C. W. (Box 8)
  - 1853 March 7, 1 item; Kennedy, G. P. (Box 8)
  - 1848 March 9, 1 item; Kennedy, J. L. (Box 8)
  - 1852-1854, 17 items; Kennedy, John P. (Box 8)
  - 1852-1853, 7 items; Kennedy, William (Box 8)
  - 1843 April 3, 1 item; Kenrick, Bishop (Box 8)
  - 1847 January 7, 1 item; Kilty, A. H. (Box 8)
  - 1846 October 21, 1 item; Kimball, William H. (Box 8)
  - 1845 April 12, 1 item; Kobeth, Henry (Box 8)
  - 1845 May 26, 1 item; Kopler, Peter C. (Pass) (Box 8)
  - 1857-1858, 6 items; Kopman, Sidney (Box 8)
  - Dinner seating arrangement, n.d.; 1 item; Kossuth, Louis (Box 8)
  - 1856 October 10, 1 item; Krebs, W. G. (Box 8)
  - Account with gunsmith, 1854; 2 items; Krider, John (Box 8)
  - 1852 November 22, 1 item; Lathrop, I. H. (Box 8)
  - 1853 March 26, 1 item; Leavitt, Joshua (Box 8)
  - 1845-1853, 6 items; Leiper, Elizabeth (Box 8)
  - 1843-1852, 16 items; Leiper, Mary T. (Box 8)
  - 1845-1853, 2 items; Leiper, S. M. (Box 8)
  - 1855, n.d., 2 items; Leiper, Thomas (Box 8)
  - 1847, n.d., 3 items; Leiper, William J. (Box 8)
  - n.d., 1 item; Lepsius, R. (Box 8)
  - 1853 March 28, 1 item; Lewis, R. F. (Box 8)
  - n.d., 1 item; Lisle, Leo (Box 8)
  - 1853 February 14, 1 item; Litchfield, J. P. (Box 9)
  - n.d., 1 item; Loomis, E. (Box 9)
  - 1852 February 16, 1 item; Loring, John W. (Box 9)
  - 1852-1856, 5 items; Lossing, Benson J. (Box 9)
  - 1853 February 1, 1 item; Lovell, William L. (Box 9)
  - 1853 January 17, 1 item; Ludlow, S. W. (Box 9)
  - 1856, 2 items; Lumley, J. Saville (Box 9)
  - 1849-1852, 3 items; Lynch, W. F. (Box 9)
  - 1849-1853, 3 items; Macalester, Charles (Box 9)
  - 1853 January 19, 1 item; Macauley, D. (Box 9)
  - 1854 December 8, 1 item; Manning, George (Box 9)
  - 1847-1848, 8 items; Mason, John Y. (Box 9)
  - 1852 January 29, 1 item; Maupin, S. (Box 9)
  - 1852-1856, 8 items; Maury, Mathew F. (Box 9)
  - 1856 October 9, 1 item; Mayer, B. (Box 9)
  - 1847 January 6, n.d., 2 items; Mayo, H. O. (Box 9)
  - 1839 January 31, 1 item; McAuley, H. W. (Box 9)
  - 1853 January 18, 1 item; McBlair, T. P. (Box 9)
  - 1853 January 22, 1 item; McBurgonyn, Mr. (Box 9)
  - 1847 May 12, 1 item; McCauley, E. G. (Box 9)
  - 1855 February 19, 1 item; McClure, Robert (Box 9)
  - 1846, 2 items; McGill, S. F. (Box 9)
  - 1848-1849, 6 items; McSherry, R. (Box 9)
  - 1849 September 9, 1 item; Meade, Edward (Box 9)
  - 1852 October 20, 2 items; Mercantile Library Association (Portland, Maine) (Box 9)
  - 1852 August 2, 1 item; Mercantile Library Association (Portland, Maine) (Box 9)
  - n.d., 1 item; Metts, H. C. (Box 9)
  - 1845 March 3, 1 item; Mexico. Ministerio De Guerra Y Marina (Box 9)
  - 1853 March 28, 1 item; Miles, P. (Box 9)
  - 1847 December 14, n.d., 3 items; Miles, S. M. (Box 9)
  - n.d., 1 item; Millar, Dr. (Box 9)
  - 1852-1853, 3 items; Mills, Robert (Box 9)
  - 1852 December 28, 1 item; Milne, Mr. (Box 9)
  - 1850, n.d., 4 items; Mitchell, Dr. (Box 9)
  - 1856, n.d., 2 items; Mitchell, S. Weir, (Silas Weir), 1829-1914 (Box 9)
  - n.d., 1 item; Morris, N. N. (Box 9)
  - 1848 September 18, 1 item; Morris, Thomas (Box 9)
  - 1857, 5 items; Morton, William (Box 9)
  - 1857 April 11, 1 item; Moxey, John G. (Box 9)
  - 1849 April 4, 1 item; Muller, W. A. (Box 9)
  - 1856-1857, 4 items; Murchison, Roderick Impey (Box 9)
  - 1852 May 6, 1 item; Murdaugh, W. H. (Box 9)
  - 1842 June 2, 1 item; Naval Board of Examiners (U.S.) (Box 9)
  - 1852, 4 items; Neal, William (Box 9)
  - 1852 October 1, 1 item; New York Yacht Club (Box 9)
  - 1856 August 7, 1 item; Nickelson, H. (Box 9)
  - 1853, 2 items; Norton, C. B. (Box 9)
  - 1841 May 3, 1 item; Oakford, John (Box 9)
  - 1853 February 27, 1 item; Ohlsen, Christian (Box 9)
  - 1854-1855, 5 items; Ohlsen, Mary (Box 9)
  - 1856, 2 items; Osborn, Sherard (Box 9)
  - 1853 January 2, 1 item; Page, T. J. (Box 9)
  - 1846-1852, 9 items; Parker, Foxhall Alexander (Box 9)
  - 1852 February 17, 1 item; Parker, John (Box 9)
  - 1844 February 15, 1 item; Parker, P. (Box 9)
  - n.d., 1 item; Parker, R. Le Roy (Box 9)
  - 1853 February 8, 2 items; Parsons, Theophilus (Box 9)
  - 1846-1847, n.d., 12 items; Patterson, Helen (Box 9)
  - 1849 January 26, 1 item; Patterson, J. D. (Box 9)
  - 1848 March 31, 1 item; Patterson,, Robert M., (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854 (Box 9)
  - 1856 May, 1 item; Paulli, J. H. (Box 9)
  - 1846 December 12, 1 item; Peabody [?] (Box 9)
  - Power of Attorney, 1837 October 30; 1 item; Peale, Titian Ramsay (Box 9)
  - n.d., 2 items; Peirce, Edwin (Box 9)
  - n.d., 1 item; Peirce, Mr. (Box 9)
  - 1852 March 5, 1 item; Pelton, C. M. (Box 9)
  - n.d., 1 item; Penny, W. (Box 9)
  - 1853 February 21, 1 item; Percy, James R. (Box 9)
  - 1852 November 20, 1 item; Perkins and Smith (Box 9)
  - 1836 January 5, 1 item; Perot, P. (Box 9)
  - n.d., 1 item; Peters, J. C. (Box 9)
  - 1856 October 8, 1 item; Peterson, Emma Bouvier (Box 9)
  - 1847, 2 items; Pettit, Robert (Box 9)
  - 1846 December 17, 1 item; Pettit, T. M. (Box 9)
  - Passport, 1844 April 29; 1 item; Philippine Islands (Box 9)
  - 1853 March, 1 item; Pierce, Franklin (Box 9)
  - 1852 November 25, 1 item; Pitman, R. C. (Box 9)
  - n.d., 1 item; Polk, James K. (Box 9)
  - Sketches, n.d.; 1 item; Porto Grande (Box 9)
  - 1855 October 19, 1 item; Potts, George (Box 9)
  - 1853 February 19, 1 item; Preble, G. H. (Box 9)
  - 1846-1847, 5 items; Prentiss, George A. (Box 9)
  - 1856, 2 items; Prescott, William H. (Box 9)
  - 1848-1852, 2 items; Preston, J. W. (Box 9)
  - 1850 May 13, 1 item; Putnam, James M. (Box 9)
  - In re Margaret Fox, 1859-1861; 20 items; Quinn, William (Box 9)
  - 1848 March 2, 1 item; Randall, D. (Box 10)
  - 1846, 9 items; Read, G. C. (Box 10)
  - 1845 April 11, 1 item; Reddie, John G. (Box 10)
  - Letters in re., 1846; 3 items; Reed, Julia (Box 10)
    Includes letter from J.T.J. (John Taylor, Jr.), Feb 4, 1846; Indenture between "Margaret Jones Smith and John Smith Jones," n.d.; and draft from E. K. K.
  - 1801-1807, 2 items; Rensselaer, Stephen van (Box 10)
  - n.d., 1 item; Resolution to Dr. Kane (Box 10)
  - 1852 October 28, 1 item; Reynolds, G. W., Jr. (Box 10)
  - n.d., 1 item; Reynolds, Mr. (Box 10)
  - 1855 February 3, 1 item; Robbins, T. W. (Box 10)
  - 1845-1851, 2 items; Robinson, William (Box 10)
  - n.d., 1 item; Rodrigo, Senon (Box 10)
  - 1856 September 8, 1 item; Roquette, de la (Box 10)